Sandun Kanangama

DATA SCIENTIST

sandunkanangama@gmail.com +61 415 532 240 linkedin.com/in/sandun-kanangama/ https://github.com/SandunKanan

PROFILE

Data Scientist with 2 years experience as an Analyst at one of Australia's big 4 banks. I've recently embarked on a professional development journey, completing two intensive 3-month bootcamps in Web Development and Data Science & Al.

I'm currently seeking Data opportunities in Tokyo. Keen to contribute to innovative projects, and my approach to work and leadership is highly focused on strong collaboration between teams in different departments.

LANGUAGES

English - Fluent

Japanese - Conversational (JLPT N4)

Sinhala - Fluent

PROJECTS & ACHIEVEMENTS

NLPalate

A review insights dashboard for restaurant owners. Utilised Natural Language Processing (NLP) Machine Learning Techniques to aggregate 500,000 phrases on Yelp into 30 topics yelp-nlpalate.streamlit.app/

FindMyCity

FindMyCity, a city recommendation engine. Normalised 300,000 lines of JSON into a SQL database using Knex.js github.com/SandunKanan/FindMyCity

BrainStation 24hr Hackathon Gold Medal

Project Manager and Lead Presenter

Dux of Mathematics, Melbourne HS

EXPERIENCE

Teaching Assistant - Software Engineering | BrainStation

MAY 2023 - AUG 2023, TORONTO, ON, CANADA

Appointed as a TA from 37 graduates to mentor the next software engineering bootcamp cohort. Responsibilities included grading coding assessments, and facilitating coding challenges and code-alongs.

 Received 100% positive feedback from cohort students, with numerous students acknowledging my role in helping them transition from self-doubt to self-assuredness in a new career.

Project Manager - Credit Risk Engine Upgrade | ANZ

SEPT 2021 - OCT 2022, MELBOURNE, VIC

Appointed to oversee our major upgrade project, responsibilities included hosting scrums and bridging knowledge gaps between tech and business.

- Enhanced project efficiency by reducing story points by over 20%, through meticulous review and collaboration with principal stakeholders
- Received an ANZ Kudos award for proactively identifying project delays across all departments, enabling ANZ to avoid regulatory fines.

Risk Systems Analyst - Counterparty Credit Risk | ANZ

MAR 2021 - JAN 2023, MELBOURNE, VIC

Responsibilities: Translating business requirements into technical specifications, performing regression testing, acceptance testing, and providing user support for our application to derivatives traders.

 Developed a python script to automate pre-release regression testing for ANZ's portfolio of 400,000 open trades, reducing average testing time from 8 hours to just 30 minutes.

Case Manager - Mortgage Debt Collections | ANZ

JUL 2019 - MAR 2021, MELBOURNE, VIC

 Consistently achieved resolution rates of 95%+ through building strong relationships and employing empathy, negotiating long term solutions with customers facing financial hardship.

EDUCATION

LeWagon Tokyo, Japan | Data Science & Al bootcamp

Skills: Machine Learning (Scikit Learn), Deep Learning (TensorFlow, LLMs), Python, Pandas, Numpy, SQL, Data Pipelines, Statistical Analysis, Hypothesis Testing, Data Visualisation, GCP, AWS, Docker, Keras

BrainStation Toronto, Canada | Software Engineering bootcamp

Skills: React, HTML, CSS, Javascript, Node, Express, Knex, Web APIs

University of Melbourne | Bachelor of Commerce (Actuarial Studies, Finance) | Melbourne, Australia

Skills: C language, R, Data Structures and Algorithms, Statistics, Annuity and Premium Calculations, Derivative Securities, Algorithmic Trading.